rishisoni6071@gmail.com

Indore (M.P.), India +91-9754370193

Professional Summary:

Started as an Intern in Web function, worked as Frontend Development Intern with Technocolabs Information Technology, with Putatoe Technologies Pvt. Ltd., and The Spark Foundation. Have the knowledge in various programming languages and regular coder on HackerRank. Have extensive experience in creating a fully Responsive and Interactive Websites.

Experience:

> Organization : The Spark Foundation

Designation : Web Development & Designing Intern

Profile : Web Application Development

From - To : Mar 2021 – Mar 2021

➤ Organization : Technocolabs

Designation : Frontend Development Intern
Profile : Web Application Development

From - To : Jun 2020 – Aug 2020

> Organization : Amstech Incorporation Pvt. Ltd.

Designation : Java Trainee

Profile : Java Development From - To : Aug 2019 – Aug 2019

Technical Skills:

Languages: JavaScript, Java, SQL, Python Basics, C, HTML5, CSS3.

Software: Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, SqlYog.

> Other Tools: Git, Postman, Trello, Bitbucket, Slack, Jira, Discord.

Good working experience with web services integration (REST API, JSON)

Experience in working with Libraries such as React, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Materialize.

Education Qualification:

Pursuing Bachelor of Technology from Acropolis Technical Campus, Indore affiliated to Rajiv Gandhi Technical University with specialization in Computer Science (2018-2022).

➤ Higher Secondary School Certificate (10+2) from MP State Board in 2018 with 83.3%.

Secondary School Certificate (10th) from MP State Board in the year 2016 with 85.6%.

Project Undertaken:

Organization : Technocolabs Information Technology

> Description : It's the Company's Official Website. Technocolabs is a Software

Development Services Company that Provide Services in Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Mobile, & Web Application Development.

➤ URL : Technocolabs Tech

> Application : Putatoe Web App

➤ Role : Frontend Web Developer

Organization : Putatoe Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

> Description : Putatoe Web App which is an eCommerce Website for Fashion and

Home Remedies. And another service for Shopkeepers to attach

their Business with us. It is still in Development phase.

Note: Please fill Location of Gorakhpur (Uttar Pradesh) Only.

➤ URL : Putatoe - Web App

➤ Application : Payment Gateway & Social Media Integration

➤ Role : Web Development & Designing Intern

Organization : The Spark Foundation

Description : Developed two prototypes in the Internship duration in which I

worked on Payment Gateway Integration & Social Media Integration.

➤ URL : <u>Payment-Gateway</u> and <u>Social-Media-Login</u>

➤ Application : Nidhiswaram Fashion
 ➤ Role : Frontend UI Developer
 ➤ Organization : Freelance Project

Description : Developed an attractive eCommerce Fashion Website for a Client with

WIX Platform.

➤ URL : <u>Nidhiswaram Fashion</u>

Personal Projects:

➤ Application : Weather Forecasting React App

> Role : Frontend Web Developer

> Description : Developed the Weather Forecasting Web App created using React &

Material-UI. It shows the current weather, today's weather of 2 hours gap, and next 3 days complete weather details. The user can see the

Weather of any country all over the world.

➤ URL : Weather Forecast App

➤ Application : Covid-19 Tracker React App
➤ Role : Frontend Web Developer

> Description : Developed the Covid-19 Tracker Web App created using React & Material-

UI. Have used the Axios Library for API Calling. It shows current graph of a

country whichever the user chooses.

➤ URL : Covid-19 Tracker

➤ Application : Vocal for Local – Web App

➤ Role : Frontend Web Developer

> Description : Developed the eCommerce Website as a College Minor Project which

provides only Indian products & feature for Shopkeepers to attach their

Business with our Platform.

URL : Vocal For Local - Web App

➤ **Application** : Google Keep Clone & Other To-Do Apps

> Role : Frontend Web Developer

> Description : Created the Google Keep Clone, other 2 fully Responsive To-do Apps using

React & Material UI Components. Have used the LocalStorage of Web

Browser for the note's storage.

➤ URL : Google Keep Clone & To-Do Apps

➤ Application : Multiple Website Templates
➤ Role : Frontend Web Developer

> Description : Created Multiple Frontend Website Designs such as Bookstore, Coffee Shop

Template, and Business Portfolio Template using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript,

Bootstrap4, & Materialize CSS.

➤ URL : Bookstore, Coffee-Shop, Business Portfolio Template

➤ **Application** : Hackathon Website – Isohack2.0

➤ Role : Lead Developer

> Description : Created the Website for College's National Level 36 Hours Hackathon.

➤ URL : <u>Isohack2.O - Web App</u>

> Application : Snake Game

> Role : Frontend Web Developer

> Description : Created the Snake Game using pure JavaScript and Canvas APIs.

➤ URL : Hungry Snake

Achievements:

Five Star Rated in Java, SQL, and JS on HackerRank.

Skills Certified in CSS and Java on HackerRank.

Personal Details:

Date of Birth : 06/07/2001

Gender : Male
Nationality : Indian
Marital Status : Unmarried
Languages known : Hindi, English

Mother Tongue : Hindi

Father's Name : Mr. Vinod Kumar Soni